<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>

<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN" "http://docbook.org/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd"
  [
  ]
>

<article>
    <articleinfo>
        <title> New features improvement and changes in mvnForum 1.0 GA </title>
        <author>
            <firstname>Tran </firstname>
            <surname> Van Hung </surname>
        </author>
    </articleinfo>
    
    <itemizedlist>
            <title> 9 new Features:  </title>
            <listitem>
                <para> Add WhirlyCache cache system to mvnforum 1.0 GA [cool]  </para>
                <para>
                    Whirlycache is a fast, configurable in-memory object cache for Java.
                    It can be used, for example, to speed up a website or an application by caching objects that would 
                    otherwise have to be created by querying a database or by another expensive procedure.
                      From the testing that we have done, 
                    it appears to be faster than any other Java cache that we have been able to inspect.
                    WhirlyCache is integrated in mvnforum 1.0 GA, it support MemberCache, PostCache, ThreadCache, ForumCache, CategoryCache (much better performance)
                    </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para> User can change forum locale in mvnforum [cool] </para>
                <para>
                Locale is a set of parameters that defines the user's language, 
                country and any special variant preferences that the user wants to see in their user interface.
                Usually a locale identifier consists of at least a language identifier and a region identifier.
                Now We can change forum locale on the fly by adding a parameter "lang" to url,
                ex: /mvnforum/mvnforum/index?lang=vi 
                </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para> Add config parameter enable_encode_url [cool]  </para>
                <para> 
               [MVNCore] : add config parameter enable_encode_url to enable/disable reponse.encodeURL
               for all link (when enable, session can be tracked by url re-writing)
               </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para> Add RSS to mvnforum 1.0 GA  </para>
                <para> 
                RSS is a family of web feed formats, specified in XML and used for Web syndication.
                RSS is used by (among other things) news websites, weblogs and podcasting
                Add RSS &lt;link rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml" /&gt; 
                to header so that Firefox can know that the page supports Live Bookmark 
                
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                         <imagedata fileref="figure/.png" format="PNG"/>
                      </imageobject>
                      <textobject>
                        <phrase>  </phrase>
                      </textobject>
                      <caption>
                         <para>
                           Live bookmark in browser 
                        </para>
                      </caption>
                      </mediaobject>
                
                </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para> Add contribtion for integration with openLDAP  </para>
                <para> 
                Lightweight Directory Access Protocol, or LDAP, is a networking protocol for querying and modifying directory services running over TCP/IP.
                An LDAP directory usually follows the X.500 model: It is a tree of entries, each of which consists of a set of named attributes with values.
                While some services use a more complicated "forest" model, the vast majority use a simple starting point for their database organization.
                Mvnforum 1.0 GA add contribtion for integration with openLDAP (please look in folder 'contrib'). With this feature, you can 
                sign on through LDAP directory service.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para> Add contribtion phpbb2mvnforum to migrate from phpBB to mvnForum  </para>
                <para> 
                Add contribtion phpbb2mvnforum to migrate from phpBB to mvnForum (thread=3030) (Thanks anandh).
                With this function, you can migrate data in phpBB database system to mvnForum's database
                </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para> Add contribtion MVNTomcatJDBCRealm to load realm from mvnForum's database  </para>
                <para> Add contribtion MVNTomcatJDBCRealm to load realm from mvnForum's database (thread=2782) (Thanks truk) </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para> Support new configuration parameter, user can config the login page  </para>
                <para> Support new configuration parameter , user can config the login page </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem>
                <para> support parameter "url" in login page, so that mvnForum can return after login successfully </para>
                <para> support parameter "url" in login page, so that mvnForum can return after login successfully </para>
            </listitem>
         </itemizedlist>
         
        <itemizedlist>
            <title> 31 Improvements: </title>
            <listitem>
                <para> Remote and customized Authenticator user now can logout if it is logged out externally [cool] </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Support double value timezone (sql script change, from INT to FLOAT) [cool] </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Change the stategy of rebuild Lucene Index, now can handle big database [cool] </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Implement JNDI for mail sessions (Thanks Mat) </para>
                <para> In the past, we config mail in mvncore.xml. We config server, username ,password for mail </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> When we config the step 1, if the mvnForumHome or the log file path are already correct, then mvnForum does not show suggestion</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Update the Rusian translation (thanks Serobit) </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Use Lucene's IndexWriter.setUseCompoundFile(true) only on disk's Directory </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Now use Directory instead of String for Lucene search index </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Now attachment is implemented with new interface BinaryStorage </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Add sample log config for loging to database in file log4j.properties </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Change the cache of forum and category to use Whirly cache </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Add new permission "Edit Own Post", now user must have this permission to be able to edit his own post and add attachment </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Add help docs for setup unicode in MySql 4.1.x and later (in file mvnForum_mysql.sql) </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Change and improve the configuration files in Admin zone</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Rewrite freeMarkerConfiguration in MVNForumConfig (thread=3170) (Thanks xmvigour) </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Now does not init mvnForum if use driver ODBC/JDBC because the limitation of this driver </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> CSS now support portlet JSR 168 </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> The logger in fatalerror.jsp now start with "com.mvnforum."</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> ContentInterceptor now allow modification of content instead of just throw exception (Change from void method to return String of new content)</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Change the behaviour of attachment: not allow to add when closed or locked </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Change the behaviour of attachment: allow to download when locked</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Update the English language for better English usage (Thanks ghpayne) (thread=2789) </para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Some update to the Intro and Admin documentation</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Add link to mvnForum Professional Services in the index page of Admin zone</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> URLEncode all the MemberName in link in all jsp files (support Chinese LoginName)</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Encode and decode cookie so if use Chinese username, it will work fine</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Change the default guest timezone with config parameter instead of hardcode (in file addmember.jsp) (Thanks huxiaonan)</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Localized hard coded strings in com.mvnforum.OnlineUserAction.getTimeString()</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Add link to viewpermision in permisionsummary</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Improve the delete non activated members, add link to the user in that page</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Log the full path of config file if there is an error to load it</para>
                <para> </para>
            </listitem>
       </itemizedlist>
</article>
